<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>security on Redouane</title>
    <link>https://red0xff.github.io/categories/security/</link>
    <description>Recent content in security on Redouane</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 18:32:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://red0xff.github.io/categories/security/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cracking the Coding Interview (literally)</title>
      <link>https://red0xff.github.io/posts/cracking_the_coding_interview_literally/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 18:32:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://red0xff.github.io/posts/cracking_the_coding_interview_literally/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Competitive programming was my entry point into computer science. I joined Hackerrank, Codechef, Project Euler and more similar platforms around 2014, to practice and improve my skills, because I was having fun solving algorithmic problems, and because I was interested in mastering at least a few programming languages (for general scripting and low-level programming mainly).
About competitive programming For those who are not familiar with this mind-sport, it&amp;rsquo;s about solving computer science problems with given constraints, for example, calculating the n-th Fibonacci number that is also prime, finding the shortest path in a graph, or finding all the ways to write a number as the sum of at least three positive numbers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redouane&#39;s Blog</title>
      <link>https://red0xff.github.io/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 09:27:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://red0xff.github.io/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my personal blog, it&amp;rsquo;s still under construction, but you can already check out some of my posts and writeups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redouane&#39;s Blog</title>
      <link>https://red0xff.github.io/achievements/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 09:27:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://red0xff.github.io/achievements/</guid>
      <description>CSAW&#39;19 CTF Finals The finals were held at NYUAD (New York University Abu Dhabi, UAE), from November 6th to November 9th 2019.
Top 10 undergraduate teams from the qualification CTF (which was held in September) were invited to the finals.
I played with Sudo_root, and we finished on the 2nd place.
(I am the guy in the middle)
HITB Cyberweek 2019 The event was held from October 14th to October 18th, at the Emirates Palace at Abu Dhabi.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When exploit mitigations are disabled on modern systems</title>
      <link>https://red0xff.github.io/posts/when_exploit_mitigations_are_disabled_on_modern_systems/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 09:27:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://red0xff.github.io/posts/when_exploit_mitigations_are_disabled_on_modern_systems/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents Introduction Prerequisites: Vulnerable program: Vulnerability Analysis of the executable Exploitation Initial plan Searching for ROP gadgets in the application Implementing the exploit Part1 - Initial Buffer overflow, stack pivoting Part2 - VirtualProtect the main module to ERW, scanf on ERW memory, and jump to it: Part3 - Final shellcode Putting it all together Conclusion Introduction While experimenting with the Windows exploit mitigation policies, I noticed that MinGW-GCC does not enable most of the modern protections by default.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
