<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>programming on Redouane</title>
    <link>https://red0xff.github.io/tags/programming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in programming on Redouane</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 11:15:58 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://red0xff.github.io/tags/programming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Inverting Keccak-f if the sponge leaks</title>
      <link>https://red0xff.github.io/posts/inverting_keccak_f/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 11:15:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://red0xff.github.io/posts/inverting_keccak_f/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  What is SHA3  Why another hash function in the SHA family? Deeper view of SHA-3  The sponge construction The internal state The Permutation function at the core of Keccak: Keccak-p  Theta: \(\theta\) Rho: \(\rho\) Pi: \(\pi\) Chi: \(\chi\) Iota: \(\iota\)   Inverting Keccak-p  \( \theta^{-1} \): Back to linear algebra \( \rho^{-1} \): Simplier than it looks \( \pi^{-1} \): Inverse transposition \( \chi^{-1} \): Non-linearity \( \iota^{-1} \): Xor again and it&amp;rsquo;ll be done \(Keccak-p^{-1}\): Just perform the inverse operations in reverse order   Example testing Implications       What is SHA3 SHA3 is a family of standarised cryptographic hashing functions, it&amp;rsquo;s the winner of the 2012 NIST hash function contest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC 2020 - Enhancing metasploit support for &#39;the Hack That Will Never Go Away&#39;</title>
      <link>https://red0xff.github.io/posts/google_summer_of_code_2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 16:45:58 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://red0xff.github.io/posts/google_summer_of_code_2020/</guid>
      <description>Table of Contents  Introduction My Proposal Community-Bonding period Results of my contribution My Google Summer of Code journey  Initial work SQLite support and specs for the library Support for PostgreSQL, and other database-management systems   Conclusion  Introduction Being interested in computer security, and being an opensource lover, I wanted to participate in Google Summer of Code this year, after checking out the list of organizations, I applied for Metasploit, because Ruby is my main programming language, and because I was very interested in contributing to a framework of this popularity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ALCPC 2018</title>
      <link>https://red0xff.github.io/about/alcpc18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://red0xff.github.io/about/alcpc18/</guid>
      <description>Algerian Collegiate Programming Contest 2018 The contest was held at University Mohamed Khider at Biskra, Algeria, from October 1st 2018 to October 3rd.
It was a programming contests, ACM ACPC qualifier. I played with the team NerDz, with students from my school, we finished on the second place, with an equal number of points as the first team (time penalty did the difference).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
